Guide to the Joseph D. Cusick Papers relating to Lockheed Missiles & Space Co. and the U.S. Air Force, 1962-1991
Department of Special Collections
Cusick, Joseph D.: Papers relating to Lockheed Missiles & Space Co. and the U.S. Air Force Satellite Test Center,
1962-1991
M1003
Joseph D. Cusick
9.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
History, policies, organization, personnel, and technical training materials collected by Joseph D. Cusick during employment. Includes the serial, TRW Space Log, 1968-1979.
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Acquisition Information
Not Available
Provenance
Not Available
Collection Scope and Content Summary
History, policies, organization, personnel, and technical trainingmaterials collected by Joseph D. Cusick during employment by Lockheed Missiles & Space Co. (LMSC) from August 1962 to May 1968 and the U.S. Air Force, at the Air Force Satellite Test Center [Satellite Operations Center] Onizuka Air Force Base, Sunnyvale, CA), from May 1962 through May 1991.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Lockheed Missiles and Space Company.; United States. Air Force. Satellite Control Facility.; Science--History.
Collection Contents
- History of Scheduling, Air Force Satellite Control Facility (AFSCF) 1962-1966 (Box AF-1)
- AFSCF Satellite Operations Resource Analysis reports 1963-1966 (Box AF-1)
- AFSCF Operations Procedures History 1965-1970 (Box AF-1)
- Air Force/Navy/Army Interrange Operations Planning Group proceedings with trip report to Cape Kennedy AFS, Florida 1966 (Box AF-1)
- "2001": A U.S. Space Force", paper from 1981 Air University Airpower Symposium at Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama 1981 (Box AF-1)
- AFSCF Historical Brief and Chronology 1954-1982 (Box AF-2)
- AFSCF operations Manual (policies and procedures for operating the satellite operations network), initial publication with changes 1966-1968 (Box AF-2)
- Conversion of contractor positions from Lockheed to Air Force 1967-1968 (Box AF-2)
- Personal files of J.D. Cusick during conversion process; correspondence with LMSC (Box AF-2)
- Papers establishing a GS-14 supervisory position in 1970 (Box AF-2)
- History of Operations Policies and Procedures, indexed 1972 (Box AF-2)
- AFSCF Program Control 1973-1974 (Box AF-2)
- Policy files from 6594 Aerospace Test Wing to AFSCF, 1962-1963 (Box AF-3)
- Satellite Test Operations history Reports 1962-1975 (Box AF-3)
- History of Operation Activation of Consolidated Space Operations Center (CSOC), U.S.Space Command) Falcon AFB, Colorado Springs, CO 1981-1991 (Box AF-4)
- Management Plan to prepare and executre training and transfer of operations personnel from Sunnyvale to Colorado Springs (Box AF-4)
- Graduation of first class of Air Force Satellite Control Officers (Box AF-4)
- renaming ceremony: Sunnyvale AFS to Onizuka AFB and transfer of facility from Air Force Systems Command to Space Command (Box AF-4)
- Contracts with Lockheed and Loral to train military satellite operators (Box AF-4)
- Photographs of construction of Consolidated Space Operations Center (Box AF-4)
- operational Activation of Consolidated Space Operations Center history Reports 1981-1991 (Box AF-5)
- Reorganization of Consolidated Space Test Command (CSTC) for MILSTAR training program 1989-1991 (Box AF-5)
- Travel files of J.D. Cusick as Department of the Air Force Civilian 1968-1991 (Box AF-5)
- training records and course materials for LMSC, Air Force Institute of Technology, U.S. Army traiing Center, Civil Service Executive Seminare Centers in Berkeley, California and Oak ridge, Tennessee, Sloan Reports from Stanford Business School 1972-1973 (Box AF-6)